Guide to the Douglas Houghton Campbell Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Douglas Houghton Campbell papers
1888-1953
SC0022
Campbell, Douglas Houghton, 1859-1953.
1.5 Linear feet
Correspondence, records of the Biology Department, class rolls, bibliography, printed works.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Biology Department, 1965.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of Botany on Stanford's first faculty (1891-1925; emeritus 1925-1953) and authority on the structure and reproduction of mosses and ferns.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, records of the Biology Department, class rolls, bibliography, printed works.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in three series: correspondence, miscellaneous papers, and printed work. Correspondents represented by a number of letters are mentioned by name in the container list.
Access Terms
Campbell, Douglas Houghton, 1859-1953.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Kellogg, Vernon Lyman.; Stanford University. Department of Zoology. Faculty.; Woodruff, Edwin Hamlin, 1862-1941.; Botany.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - A letters, B.E. Allandice, American Association for the Advance of Science (Albert L. Barrows)., 1888 Aug. 24 -1922 Jan. 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B letters, D. O. Bower, N. L. Britton., 1888 Aug. 14 -1947 Aug. 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C letters, Albert P. Carman, L. Cockaque, E. B. Copeland, John M. Coulter., 1888 Sept. 11 1944 Aug. 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D letters, Bradley Moore Davis, C. W. Dodge., 1888 Dec. 4 -1953 Jan. 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - E letters, Alexander W. Evans., 1888 Oct. 8 -1921 Apr (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - F letters, David Fairchild, W. E. Farlow., 1903 Sept. 30 -1945 Aug. 5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - G letters, Ginn & Co., Frank F. Gunn., 1889 Nov. 19 -1944 Sept. 18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - H letters, Richard M. Holman, Marshall A. Howe, A. B. Humphrey., 1889 Feb. 26 -1944 Sept. 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - I letters, 1899 Jan. 21 -1915 May 15. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - J letters, Duncan S. Johnson, David Starr Jordan., 1888 Aug. 13 -1919 Mar. 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - K letters, Vernon L. Kellogg., 1889 Sept. 30 -1920 Nov. 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - L letters, Harold L. Lyon., 1914 Sept. 14 -1944 Oct. 27 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - M letters, D. MacDougal, MacMillan & Co., D. M. Mottier., 1892 May 21 -1917 Oct. 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - N letters, F. C. Newcombe, National Academy of Sciences., 1889 June 14 -1938 Mar. 16 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - O letters, 1897 Dec. 23 -1915 Dec. 24. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - P letters, Alma Pfeffer, C. J. Peirce., 1897 Dec. 18 -1947 Apr. 3 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - R letters, 1891 Nov. 18 -1920 Apr. 10 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - S letters, D. H. Scott, Walter R. Shaw, W. M. Spalding., 1888 Sept. 11 -1952 Apr. 7 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - T letters, Francis R. Thompson., 1903 June 27 -1944 Aug. 6 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - U letters, L. M. Underwood., 1889 June 1 -1920 Feb. 3 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - V letters, Sidney H. Vines., 1891 Mar. 10 -1945 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - W letters, John C. Willis, Edwin H. Woodruff., 1890 Mar. 5 -1947 Oct. 22 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - XYZ letters, 1898 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Unknown letters, 1898 June 9 -1903 May 28. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous Papers
  - Biology Department records and correspondence, 1915-1922. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Four class roll books, a plant record, and three photographs. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Typescript of "Australian Botanical Notes." (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Clippings: short printed articles and reviews. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Campbell bibliography. (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Printed Works
  - Printed articles (listed in folder 29). (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - The Structural and Systematic Botany by D. H. Campbell. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - The Evolution of Plants, by D. H. Campbell. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Plant Life and Evolution, by D. H. Campbell. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Mosses and Ferns, by D. H. Campbell, 2 copies, 1905 and 1913. (Box 3, Folder 34)